

# Manoj M

Bangalore, 560100 +91 949-409-1954 infymp54@gmail.com

# PROFESSIONAL O SUMMARY

To contribute to a solution oriented, team environment. Maximize interpersonal and organizational skills and knowledge. Engage in opportunities to utilize experience and motivation, including learning new technologies, to provide professional growth for both the company, and myself

# **HONORS & AWARDS**

#### **INSTA AWARD**

Issued by Infosys · Mar 2023

Appreciated efforts, skills and contribution in the Linux team. Keep up the good work!

### Infosys - (RISE Celebrating Excellence)

Nov 2022

Awarded by GPM for the efficient handle of Linux track in SD domain.

# **Cognizant - (Support and Projects)**

Jan 2019Jan

**ACE OF ROOKIES** 

# SKILLS ()

Operating System: Linux (Redhat, CentOS, SuSE, Ubuntu), Windows server.

Installations: FTP, NFS, KICKSTART. Servers: DNS, DHCP, NFS, SAMBA,

Web server: Apache 2.4, Tomcat 8.5.24. Cloud.

VMware vSphere 6.5. 6.7.0.

Data Protector Manager 10.3 HP Lights-Out Stand Alone ILO5

Remote console:

Monitoring Tools: Nagios, Cacti, IBM

QRadar.

Other: Knowledge on Linux High

Availability Clustering, KACE System

Management Appliance.

Knowledge on Amazon Web services

Datacenter Technologies: Virtualization: Knowledge on installation of **Jenkins** and integrating with Git, Maven. Managing tool for Backup: Micro Focus Knowledge on **Ansible Automation**.

- [Type] Software Proficiency
- Multitasking Abilities

#### WORK HISTORY

#### **TECH LEAD - LINUX**

11/2022 to CURRENT

#### (Caterpillar Inc) | Infosys Ltd, Bangalore

• Working as a Team Lead for Linux & Unix track - End to end management of the whole track which consist of 12 members.

- Being major part of hosting services division by maintaining and managing 5000+ RHEL servers (Non-Prod and Prod).
- Have good experience in working on all server management related activities which include identifying hardware and software solutions, troubleshooting technical issues, diagnosing and expediting faults related to OS.
- Experience in working on critical and high priority tickets and also directly dealing on technical escalations.
- Have relevant experience in working on all critical changes done to infrastructure end (Linux).
- Experience in handling Satellite, Manual and Cloud patching.
- Experience in handling migration activity from on prem to Cloud.
- Have good knowledge in handling IT Compliance SOX audit.
- Handled various tech meetings with client and other senior level management.
- Automated manual tasks using shell scripting in Linux environment.
- Resolved problems, improved operations and provided exceptional service.
- Exhibit exceptional leadership qualities.

#### SENIOR LINUX SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

08/2021 to 11/2022

#### Collagro Solutions India Pvt.LTD | Bangalore

- Providing L1& L2 support in 24/7.
- Providing day-to-day user administration like adding, deleting and password aging and Perform daily system monitoring, verifying the integrity and availability of all hardware, server resources, systems, network and processes and Troubleshooting of day-to-day issues such as logging in, network, disk space, and permission issues.
- Track and own all incident and problem managements work through ticketing system.
- Resolved and provided the Root Cause Analysis (RCA) for the daily incidents like system reboot, high load.

#### SYSTEM ENGINEER

02/2021 to 08/2021

#### CACHATTO India Pvt Ltd | Bangalore

- Installation, configurations and managing Redmine.
- Installation, configurations and managing BackupPC software for backing up the shared folders.
- Installation, configurations and managing CRM like SuiteCRM for Sales Team.
- Installation, configurations and managing samba Server.
- Creating SMB users SMB Passwords for new users.

- Creating Activity Documents.
- Installation, configurations and managing HA Proxy, Traefik Load Balancers.
- Monitoring and Managing Cahatto ESXI Hosts.
- Installation, configurations Redhat, Centos Machines for Developers and QA.
- Installation, configurations and managing Cachatto Products in clients environment.
- Creating Managing Automated backup Schedule tasks.
- Creating, updating and deleting automated backup and restoration schedules.
- Worked as a Linux and Virtualization expert and leading the project for Industry security management (ISM) proposed by CACHATTO to the clients for accessing their high-end manufacturing machines remotely and doing the log analysis for performance improvements.
- Knowledge of working with the Virtual Desktop Appliances and solutions like VMWare Horizon, CACHATTO Desktop and Checkpoint Capsule.
- Client support, worked on troubleshooting issues and providing best solutions as per the client's requirements.
- Worked on market analysis, oversee upgrades and installations along with negotiations with vendors.
- Communication with internal and external developers of products and systems and Promotes the organization's capabilities to clients, identifies sales opportunities to be forwarded to the account managers, and achieves contract extensions or additional business within the account(s).

#### SERVER SUPPORT ENGINEER

07/2019 to 02/2021

#### Xaas Infotech Pvt Ltd(Mangalore Refinery And Petr) | Bangalore

- Good hands on experience on VMware. Tasks like Installing & Managing ESXi, vCenter, Configuring and Managing the Network, Storage, Virtual Machines.
- VSphere Management, Monitoring and Performance, Backup and Disaster Recovery, Implementation and Management, VMware Site Recovery Manager.
- Working experience on Micro Focus Data Protector Manager.
- Monitor and resolving issues of backup failures in Micro Focus Data Protector.
- Backup/Copy/Consolidation jobs scheduling in Micro Focus Data protector.
- Working knowledge on KACE System Management Appliance.
- Hands on experience on Linux Clustering.
- Managing HA Cluster activities like Enabling and Disabling the Cluster Services, Adding and Removing a Cluster Nodes, Standby and Unstandby

Nodes, Fencing Configuration, Quorum Operations, Creating and Configuring Resources, Troubleshooting Resources Failures, Configuring ISCSI Targets and Initiators, LVM, Global File System.

- Jboss Application services start and stop.
- Accessing server through console (HP OA, ILO) when servers are not reachable.
- Remote health monitoring of servers & storage in the disaster recovery (DR) site for MRPL.
- Troubleshoot & Replace hardware in case of hardware failures.
- Mount and Unmount File systems based on the user specification.
- Monitor Data Protector Backups and ensure that minimal failures.
- Installing Data Protector GUI on various systems.
- Adding Client Server into the Data Protector Manager.
- Maintaining and Changing the Tapes for production and Non-Production Backups.
- Restoring the Data on required basis.
- Creating a Media Pool on request basis
- Performing back up activities on Daily/Weekly/Monthly wise.

#### ASST. SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

04/2017 to 06/2019

# Nisarga Information Technology Solutions Pvt. Ltd | Hyderabad

- Cracking and reset root password for Linux machines.
- Responsible for installation, configuration, management and maintenance over Linux systems.
  - Remote Administration of Linux server using ssh, vnc viewer.
- Installation & Configuration of various Linux flavours such as Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6.0, 7.0 and SUSE Linux Enterprise 12-sp3-SAP and Centos.
- Creating and Managing the File Systems.
   Filesystem investigation to find out why threshold has been passed and fixing as required.
- General troubleshooting supported the audit teams.
- Documentation of each team member procedure.
- Installation, configurations and managing different File Servers like NFS, FTP.
- Configuration of NFS clients for file sharing.
- Configuration of FTP and remote application like ssh, scp, telnet.
- Configuration of different RAIDS RAID 0, RAID 1 and RAID 5 on Linux.
- Configuration of Virtualization.
- Configuring the LVM (Logical Volume Manager) and extended the logical volumes.
- Writing shell scripts on automation concepts and scheduling jobs using

- those scripts for daily tasks.
- Diagnosing user related issues and providing solutions to them; Backup and restoration by using tar.
- Diagnosing, monitoring performance and network related issues using ps, top, netstat, ss.
- Responsible for creating, modifying and deleting users, groups and assigning the permissions to Users and Groups.
- Configuring and Maintaining the ACLs (Access Control Lists) for users.
- Configure IP addresses, Subnet Masks and Gateway Addresses on Routers and Hosts.
  - Creating a Swap Partition.
- Worked experience in SELinux Context, Modes of Linux, Disabling & Enabling the Security.
- Creating Physical Volumes (PV), Volume Groups (VG), Logical Volumes (LV).
- Remote Installation of Linux OS, Unattended Installation (Kick start Installation).
- Capable of preparing scripts from project perspective.
- Remote administration of manageable Routers & Switches with Telnet and
- Assigning manual and automatic ip addresses by using nmtui and nmcli.
- Configuring NTP clients using chrony package.
   Remote shell access using SSH, password less login using SSH key and remote.

2017

#### **EDUCATION** $\bigcirc$

# MASTER OF TECHNOLOGY NEWTONS INSTITUTE OF ENGINEERING, Jawaharlal Nehru

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- RHCSA Red Hat Certified System Administrator (180-058-794)
- RHCE Red Hat Certified Engineer (180-058-794)
- **Professional vSphere 6.7** ( 361945118 )
- ITIL 2011 Foundation- Infosys (LMVLJ51WMD)
- AZ 900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals (OV5HKOIWPR)